Tyler Caprioli

Mount Vernon, NY-willing to relocate | (347) 918-6982 | <u>Capriolityler@gmail.com</u> github.com/TCaprioli | medium.com/@caprioli.tyler | personal portfolio/website URL

JOB TITLE

My passion for software development is inspired by a desire to write code in a thoughtful, yet clean and efficient manner. I am primarily experienced with Ruby on Rails and JavaScript frameworks. I attribute my success in overcoming technical obstacles to my real-world experience in the Army Reserves. During my five-year service (including one year overseas) I developed skills in leadership and strengthened my ability to work well with others while under the pressure of tight deadlines.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Ruby, Rails, Postgres, SQLite, Javascript, React, Redux

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Sonata - Github | Demo

Music player SPA that allows users to create playlists and "like" their favorite songs

- Implemented DOM manipulation, event listeners, and data fetching in vanilla Javascript to make interactive components
- Built a custom rails API with five models
- Styled and organized with CSS

Wavbox - Github | Demo

Social-media application that allows users to upload videos and subscribe to other user's profile

- Applied bcrypt and backend authorizations to encrypt user passwords and allow for user logins.
- Experimented with a self-referential model to conduct user-to-user interaction.
- Utilized Active Storage to hold video uploads

App Name - Github | Demo

Brief description of the app's functionality and purpose

- Action verb + what you did + result
- Action verb + what you did + result
- Action verb + what you did + result
- Action verb + what you did + result

EXPERIENCE

United States Army Reserves

Saugerties, NY

Combat Engineer/Corporal/Team Leader

01/2015 - Present

- Coordinated with my team to accomplish time-sensitive missions
- Oversaw the tracking and movement of 200+ personnel during Kuwait and Afghanistan deployments

City College of New York

New York, NY

Custodial Assistant

08/2016 - 12/2020

- Managed essential upkeep for several buildings; including but not limited to stripping and waxing, carpet cleaning, vacuuming, floor care, trash removal, changing lights and restroom sanitation.
- Assisted in outdoor projects around the college, such tasks included picking weeds, raking leaves, garbage pick-up, shoveling snow, bulk trash removal, and general ground maintenance

EDUCATION

Flatiron SchoolFull Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

O1/ 2020 - 04/2020